David de Esteban Cortés Software Engineer

estdav@protonmail.com • +34 656 552 448 • Jávea, Alicante (Spain)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-de-esteban • https://github.com/EstDavid/

Skills

Full Stack Development and Software Engineering: JavaScript | TypeScript | Git | React | Next.js | Figma | PostgreSQL | Node.js | Express.js

AI Tools: OpenAI API | VS Code with GitHub Copilot | VO for rapid prototyping | Agents

Web3: Solidity | ethers.js

Profile

Full-Stack Software Developer with strong experience building modern web applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB. Currently working on a real estate platform, contributing to both frontend and backend development. Previously developed multiple Web3 applications, including building and integrating responsive interfaces that interact with smart contracts on Ethereum-compatible networks

Experience

Jessica Bataille, Fullstack Developer 🛭

April 2024 - present | Jávea, Spain

Jessica Bataille is a Design and Architecture studio. My role as fullstack developer is to boost the creation of the company's first digital app (https://www.popinhome.com/en 🖸):

- Created admin panel from 0 for real estate app, establishing coding patterns to ensure escalability and maintainability
- Worked closely with backend team, adding functionality as needed
- Collaborated with frontend in bringing Figma designs to fully functional code
- Created complete test suite for backend
- Implemented Stripe integration for web app version
- Integrated AI chat functionality to rapidly generate property reports (architecture, interior design, engineering, etc)

Pura Vida, Mobile Developer

2023 - 2024 | Remote, Spain

Pura Vida is an App that allows festival-goers to find their way in a summer festival and create their own agenda of activities.

- Simplified the app's design using React Native, aligning it with the festival's branding, enhancing user experience.
- Currently collaborating on backend for organizers, focusing on intuitive UI with Next.js and Tailwind CSS.

CADO, Full Stack Developer

2023 - 2024 | Remote, Spain

CADO is a Mobile web application helping pet owners to find pet sitters, and pet sitters to manage pet stays and send updates

- Key contributor in a 5-member team, focusing on frontend development of a pet-sitting platform with React and Next.js.
- Led the UI styling with Tailwind CSS, ensuring consistency with prototypes from Figma, enhancing user engagement.

UniCharts, Blockchain Developer

2022 - 2023 | Remote, Lithuania

Charting App showing price data from Uniswap V3 pools

• Developed a charting application to translate complex price data from liquidity pools into user-friendly interfaces.

Delta Radar, Blockchain Developer

2021 - 2022 | Remote, Lithuania

App that finds arbitrage trades in ETH & BSC blockchains

• Implemented frontend for a blockchain-based app with React.js, highlighting skills in developing responsive web apps.

Roles as Mechanical Engineer

2003 - 2020

As mechanical engineer I took on various roles in the rolling stock industry (locomotives, trains, etc):

- Engineer of mechanical installations (Stadler, 2019 2020)
- Mechanical engineer (NSTM, Dutch Railways, 2016 2018)
- Engineering business developer (Decnika, 2013 2016)
- Mechanical systems engineer (Vossloh, 2003 2012)

Education

Industrial Engineering, Universidad Politécnica de Valencia

1997 - 2003

Software Engineering, Codeworks

2024

Fullstack Open Course, University of Helsinki

2023